WIND
(カカシ)ようこそ
おいでくださいました。
Welcome.
(我愛羅)久しぶりだな 六代目。
It's been a while Lord Sixth.
遅くなってすまない。
I apologize for being late.
他の影たちは
もう到着しておられるか？
Have the other Kage
arrived already?
えぇ ちょうど今しがた
到着されましたよ。
Yes, they just arrived.
水影がいないようだが？
6TH HOKAGE
I don't see the Mizukage…
(シズネ)
道中 天候が悪化したせいで→
6TH HOKAGE
Due to inclement weather en route,
半日ほど
到着が遅れてしまうそうです。
6TH HOKAGE
they are running about
a half a day behind.
6TH HOKAGE
During this time,
(カカシ)せっかくですから
それまでの間→
6TH HOKAGE
please relax and enjoy what
our village has to offer.
里で おくつろぎください。
I've assigned Hidden Leaf Shinobi
to accompany you.
木ノ葉の忍たちに
案内させますので。
By the way, Lord Sixth.
(オオノキ)時に六代目
ナルトが祝言をあげるそうじゃが？
I understand Naruto is
going to marry.
Yes, so you've heard?
えぇ ご存じでしたか。
I've prepared a wedding gift
from the Hidden Rock.
岩隠れの里からということで
祝いの品を用意したのじゃが→
May I ask you to present it
at the wedding celebration?
祝言に贈る手はずを
整えてもらえんか？
The Hidden Cloud will
also be sending a gift.
(エー)我ら雲隠れの里からも
祝うつもりだ。 同様に頼む。
I ask the same of you.
I understand.
(カカシ)わかりました。
それはナルトも喜ぶことでしょう。
I'm sure Naruto will
be very happy.
Naruto…is getting married, huh?
ナルトが 祝言か…。
The Kazekage's Wedding Gift
We didn't hear anything about
Naruto getting married!
(カンクロウ)ナルトが祝言をあげるなんて
聞いてなかったじゃん。
Temari, you were here just
a little while ago…
(カンクロウ)テマリ！ お前 この間も
木ノ葉に来てたんだから→
You must've heard about it!
Y-Yeah…
聞いてただろ。
(テマリ)あ あぁ…。
Why didn't you tell us?!
なんで伝えなかったじゃん！
Shut up! I forgot, okay?!
What's come over you?
うるさい 忘れてただけだ！
Y-You're being scary.
どうしたんだ 急に。
(カンクロウ)な… なんか怖いじゃん。
In any case, we should
prepare a wedding gift.
とにかく 我々も
何か祝いの品を用意したいな。
Since it will be from the Kazekage,
we should get something extravagant.
風影として盛大に祝ってやろうぜ。
Extravagant, huh?
Do you think Naruto would
appreciate that?
盛大にか…
それで ナルトが喜ぶだろうか？
You think Naruto wouldn't be happy
with something extravagant?
盛大にやって
ナルトが喜ばないと思うか？
CONGRATULATIONS!
そう言われてみれば…。
(リー)我愛羅君 お久しぶりです！
When you put it that way…
Gaara! It's been a very long time!
あぁ 久しぶり…。
水影様が到着するまで→
Yes, it certainly has.
We are going to show you
around the village
僕たちが
我愛羅君たちの案内役を→
務めることになりました。
(テンテン)ちょっと リー。
until Lord Mizukage arrives!
今日は五影会談で
いらっしゃってるわけだし→
Hey, Lee.
He's here for
the Five Kage Conference
私たちも任務なんだから
そんなにフランクに接しちゃダメでしょ。
and we're on duty as well.
Don't get too casual.
いや
そんなことは気にしないでいい。
No, let's not stand on ceremony.
頼んだぞ。
楽しみにしてるじゃん。
We appreciate your company.
We're looking forward to it.
では早速ですが
どこか行きたい所はありますか？
So, is there somewhere
you want to go first?
そうだな…。
Let's see…
何か ナルトの好きなものを
知りたいんだが。
Actually, I want to know
what kinds of things Naruto likes.
ナルトの好きなもの… ですか。
そうですね。
What Naruto likes?
Let's see…
あ！ だったら よい所があります。
早速 案内しましょう。
I know just the place!
I'll take you there now!
(我愛羅)よし ２人も来るだろ？
(カンクロウ)もちろんじゃん。
Great. Are you both coming?
Of course!
私は ここで休ませてもらうよ。
I'm just going to relax here.
《あいつに出くわしたら
気まずいしな》
It will be awkward if I run into him.
どうした テマリ？
妙にイラだってるじゃん。
What's up, Temari?
You seem weirdly irritated…
べっ べつに何でもないから！
There's nothing going on!
You guys just go!
あんたたちだけで
行ってきなさいよ。
RAMEN ICHIRAKU
(テウチ)う～ん… う～ん…。
Hello!
(イルカ)こんにちは。
お イルカ先生 いらっしゃい。
Oh! Welcome, Iruka Sensei!
I'd like a large miso char siu ramen.
みそチャーシュー大盛り お願いします。
(アヤメ)は～い。
Sure thing!
But, Iruka Sensei, you've been
coming around a lot lately.
ていうか 最近
来すぎじゃないですか イルカ先生。
Don't be rude, Ayame!
余計なこと言うな アヤメ。
大事な お客さんじゃねえか。
He's a very important customer!
What's going on with you?
You seem to be troubled.
ハハハハ！
それより どうしたんです？
悩んでるみたいでしたけど。
Well…
いやねぇ… ここんところ
ナルトたちの結婚祝いのことで→
Everyone's in a tizzy over
what to get Naruto
for his wedding gift for
the past few days.
みんな
盛り上がってるじゃねえですか。
It doesn't involve me
since I'm not a shinobi.
But I still want to give him something.
And I came up with…
俺も祝ってやりてえ。
なもんで 俺なりに考えたのが
これなんですがね。
this!
FREE RAMEN PASS
ICHIRAKU
A free ramen pass?
ラーメンフリーパス？
Oh! Not this.
あ ちょっ… そうじゃねえ。
RAMEN FREE PASS
FOR ONE YEAR
ICHIRAKU
I see… He gets to eat free ramen
for a limited time.
なるほど ラーメンを無料で食べられる
定期券ってことですか。
I'm sure this'll make him
very happy.
But I wonder about a whole year…
たしかに喜ぶでしょうけど→
あいつの場合
１年でも どうかな…。
１年は長いよ。
長すぎだ。
半年でも同じじゃない？
そうだよなぁ…。
(リー)なるほど 我愛羅君も→
ナルト君に結婚祝いを贈るんですね。
絶対 喜ぶはずです。
ということは
リーも祝いの品を用意したんだな？
A year is too long.
Too long…
もちろんです！
そうか。
RAMEN FREE PASS
FOR SIX MONTHS
ICHIRAKU
結婚祝いを選ぶなど
初めてだからな。
It's the same with half a year.
Yeah, you're right…
どんなものを選ぶべきか
まったく見当がつかん。
I see.
You want to give Naruto
a wedding gift too?
それならまず
結婚式とはなんなのかを→
He'll definitely be overjoyed!
考えるところから始めるべきです。
あっ。
So, does that mean
you have something already, Lee?
((ガイ : そもそも
結婚式とは なんなんだ？
Of course!
I see.
結婚式に絶対必要なものとは
なんだ？
This is the first time I'm getting
something like a wedding gift.
(愛… なのではないでしょうか？))
I don't have a clue
on what to get.
《なんか嫌な予感》
Then you must consider what
a wedding is in the first place!
結婚式とは何か… か。
なかなか哲学的な質問だな。
What is a wedding ceremony?
そうなんです。
なので こう考えてみてください。
What is absolutely necessary
for a wedding ceremony?
結婚式に絶対必要なものは何かと。
Wouldn't that be…love?
結婚式に必要なものか…。
I'm getting a bad feeling
about this…
愛… なんじゃねえか。
"What is a wedding ceremony?"
That's a very philosophical question.
Yes, it is.
はい！ 僕もまさに
そう考えていたんです！
So think about it this way…
What is absolutely necessary
for a wedding ceremony?
なんで見事に同じ展開になるの！
Absolutely necessary for
a wedding…?
しかし 僕の尊敬する師匠
ガイ先生は その考えにとどまらず→
Wouldn't that be…love?
結婚式に大事なのは
新郎と新婦であると思いつき→
Yes!
LOVE
That was my answer too!
２人の立場になって考えれば→
LOVE
Why is this going exactly
the same way as before?!
おのずと贈るべきものは
見えてくると説かれたのです。
However, my mentor whom
I greatly respect, Guy Sensei,
その結果…。
didn't stop there.
ダンベルを贈ることになりました！
He realized that
it's the bride and groom
who are most important
in a wedding…
ダ… ダンベル？
and if you put yourself
into their shoes,
僕は一介の忍ですから
そのくらいが ちょうどよいかと。
you would see what would
be the best gift.
でも 我愛羅君は 風影という
立場もありますし→
And the result of that was…
ここは派手に バーベルなんて
よいのではないでしょうか。
I got them dumbbells!
D-Dumbbells?
バ… バーベルか。
I'm only a shinobi…
so I think that's most suitable thing
for me to present.
バーベルはどうかと思うが→
However, Gaara, you are the Kazekage,
so we must consider your position.
その派手にってところは
俺も賛成じゃん。
So, I think some extravagant barbells
would be great!
(リー)こんにちは。
(テウチ)らっしゃい！
イルカ先生！
やぁ リー君 また会ったね。
B-Barbells, huh…
我愛羅君 ナルト君の恩師の
イルカ先生です。
I don't know about barbells…
But I agree with
the "extravagant" part.
イルカ先生
こちらは風影の我愛羅君です。
ICHIRAKU
– Hello!
– Welcome!
は はじめまして！
Iruka Sensei!
風影様が
なんで リー君たちと一緒に？
Hey, Lee! We meet again!
Gaara, let me introduce Iruka Sensei,
Naruto's teacher.
五影会談が始まるまで➡
私たちが 里の案内役を
務めているんです。
Iruka Sensei,
this is Gaara the Kazekage!
我愛羅君も ナルト君の結婚祝いを
どうしようかと考えてるんですよ。
H-How do you do?
Why is Lord Kazekage
with you two?
ナルト君と我愛羅君は
友達ですからね。
We've been assigned to show him
around the village
友達…。
until the Five Kage Conference begins.
とにもかくにも
砂隠れの里を代表して→
Gaara is also thinking about
a wedding gift for Naruto.
盛大に祝ってやるじゃん。
Naruto and Gaara are friends.
風影様がナルトのために
盛大に祝ってくださるなんて→
Friends?!
恐れ多いことですが
ナルトのやつも必ず喜ぶはずです。
Anyway, we're going to send
an extravagant gift
では 失礼します。
representative of the Hidden Sand.
I'm very grateful to
the Lord Kazekage
for making such
an extravagant gesture…
and I'm sure Naruto will
be overjoyed as well.
なっ ナルトも喜んでくれるってよ。
Now, if you will please excuse me.
先生が言うなら お墨つきじゃん。
そうなのか？
確かに ナルトは
派手なの大好きだからな。
See? Naruto's gonna be happy!
盛大に祝ってやって
喜ばないはずはねえぜ。
そうか…。
His own teacher confirmed that.
俺もやっぱり盛大に
１年間くらい フリーパス…。
You think so?
One thing's for sure,
Naruto loves flashy things!
お父さん！
は… はい。
There's no way he won't be happy
with an extravagant gift.
親父さん みそチャーシュー大盛り
お願いします。
I see…
I guess I'm gonna go
big and grand too,
なんだそれは？
ナルト君の好きなメニューです。
and give him a year's free pass—
Father…
チャーシューが盛大に
盛られているんです。
Y-Yes…
Pops, I'll have a large
miso char siu ramen!
ラーメンも盛大か。
じゃあ俺もそれをもらおう。
What is that?
Naruto's favorite item
on the menu.
じゃあ 俺もじゃん。
では 親父さん→
It has an extravagant helping
of char sui.
みそチャーシュー大盛りを
人数分お願いします。
Even his ramen is extravagant?
ちょっと待って。
私は 普通盛り チャーシュー抜きで。
Then I'll have that too.
Me too.
トッピングは…。
トッピング？
Okay, Pops…
A large miso char siu ramen
for all of us!
ナルトが１位なんですね。
Hold it!
(テウチ)以前はトッピングの中でも
いちばん人気がなかったが→
Make mine a regular,
without char siu, and for the topping…
ここ最近は ひとり勝ちよ！
Topping?
Seems Naruto fish cake
is ranked number one.
これも ナルト効果だな。
じゃあ 私 みそラーメン普通盛りに
ナルトをトッピングで。
Way back, it used to be
the least popular.
These days, it's Naruto fish cake,
hands down.
ならば俺も
それを追加してもらおう。
That's the kinda effect he's had.
(テウチ)はいよ！ こうなったら
トッピングも盛大に盛ってやるぜ！
Then I'll have
the regular miso ramen,
with the Naruto fishcake topping.
いやぁ 食ったじゃん。
Please add that to mine too.
TOPPING MENU
#1 NARUTO FISHCAKE
#2 CHAR SIU
#3 MENMA
All right! I'll give you an extravagant
helping of the topping!
次は どこに行きましょうかね。
大丈夫ですか？
Boy, did we eat.
さっきから考え事ばかり
してるみたいですけど。
Where would you like to go next?
風影として ナルトを
どう祝うべきか考えていてな。
Are you all right?
You've been deep in thought
this whole time.
風影として？
カンクロウは盛大にやりたいようだが
俺は あまりピンときていなかった。
I was thinking about what
to give Naruto as the Kazekage.
そうでしたか。
おいおい 我愛羅。
As the Kazekage?
Kankuro wants to give
something extravagant,
しかし ナルトの恩師や
ラーメン屋の主人の話を聞いて→
but that just doesn't sit right with me.
I see…
吹っ切れた。
Hey, c'mon, Gaara…
ナルトが喜ぶならばな。
そうこなくっちゃよ！
But after listening to
Naruto's teacher
and the ramen shop's proprietor,
I'm convinced.
僕も
できるかぎりお手伝いします！
As long as it makes Naruto happy.
(みんな)ん？
That's more like it!
I'll help in any way I can too!
(キラービー)え？
♪♪「あ～ お前らは
砂隠れ 木ノ葉隠れ」
– Huh?
♪♪「そういう俺様は誰 イエー」
Huh?
Hey, you Hidden Sand
and Leaf guys!
《下手なラップ》
雷影様の護衛の
キラービーさんですね。
Guess who I am, yay!
里の案内は
してもらってないんですか？
What an awful rap…
You're Lord Killer Bee,
the bodyguard of Lord Raikage, right?
♪♪「俺様は自由を好む フリーダム」
Isn't anyone accompanying you
in the village?
♪♪「ブラザーたちは 接待で会食中」
I prefer my freedom.
♪♪「俺様は 里を徘徊中」
My brother's at
the conference reception.
♪♪「風影… あんたらも
ナルトの結婚祝い 用意する予定？」
Me, I prefer a village exploration.
By the way, Kazekage,
あぁ そのつもりだが。
are you planning on giving
Naruto a wedding gift?
♪♪「その件に関して
俺様がとりしきる役目」
Yes, I intend to.
♪♪「互いに頑張ろうぜ イエー！」
Finding a gift is
my personal mission.
雲隠れからのお祝いは
ノリがよさそうね…。
Let's do our best to make
a good decision, yay.
♪♪「俺たちからの祝い
聞いて驚け！ 聞いておけ！」
Sounds like the Hidden Cloud
are really into this.
Our gift will be something
to marvel at.
《テンテン : ほんと いちいち ラップで
返してくるの 面倒くさい…》
Listen well and remember that.
♪♪(キラービー)「鏡開き用の
雲隠れ産の酒を四斗樽！」
Seriously? Do you have to answer
in rap all the time?
♪♪「全部で10樽 イエー！」
PURE SAKE
LONG LIFE
LIGHTNING
CONGRATULATIONS
Decorated for a special occasion…
PURE SAKE
LONG LIFE
LIGHTNING
CONGRATULATIONS
Sake produced by the Hidden Cloud…
♪♪「超高級雲隠れ産 牛肉」
Ten giant kegs of which
we're proud, yay.
♪♪「１頭分を丸々 提供！
丸焼き盛況！ イエー！」
Hidden Cloud beef of
super high-quality…
We'll present it roasted whole,
in its entirety, yay.
♪♪「ゲームの景品で
人気ゲーム機 盛大に10台 イエー！」
Premium games…
The best of the best.
♪♪「ざっと こんな感じ
結婚祝いは大事」
Ten great games, no less. Yay!
That sums up my presentation.
♪♪「イエー！」
すごいです！
A wedding's an important celebration.
Yay.
ラップのせいで すんなり
頭に入ってこなかったけど→
A-Amazing!
I didn't get the details
because of your rap…
とりあえず
豪華なことは わかったわ。
but I did get that
it'll be extravagant.
♪♪「それで お前ら 砂隠れは
何を贈るんだ？」
So what's the Hidden Sand getting?
♪♪「とっくに 発注済んだ？」
Have you already ordered it?
うむ それがだな…。
Well…that's just it.
♪♪「オーケー オーケー！
俺様が気づかなかった ソーリー！」
Okay! Okay!
I apologize, I should have realized…
♪♪「俺たちが豪華すぎて
お前たちは言えな～い」
Our gifts are so extravagant
that it's made you hesitant.
♪♪「でも それは しかたな～い」
(カンクロウ)あぁ？
But that's not important.
♪♪(キラービー)「大事なのは ハート
豪華じゃなくても 必ず喜ぶ ナルト」
Huh?
Doesn't matter
if it's not fancy,
what comes from the heart
is the best choice.
♪♪「イエー！」
That's what'll make
Naruto rejoice, yay!
甘く見るんじゃねえ！
Don't patronize us!
カ… カンクロウ…。
K-Kankuro?!
俺たちだって 雲隠れと同じくらい
祝うに決まってるじゃん！
We're gonna give a gift that
equals the Hidden Cloud's!
披露宴会場は 砂隠れ産の花で
埋め尽くすつもりじゃん！
We plan to cover the reception hall
with flowers grown in
the Hidden Sand!
更に パーティーの食事に
花を添えるために→
And to highlight
the celebration dinner,
高級マグロを１本 贈るじゃん！
we'll send the finest tuna
in the land…a whole bluefin!
引き出物のための菓子折りだって
来客者全員分 用意するじゃん！
And we'll prepare boxes of sweets
as wedding favors for every guest!
ざっと こんなもんじゃん！
How's that?!
(我愛羅)待て 誰が そんな…。
すごいです！
Hold it. Who said anything about—?
Amazing!
短時間の間に これだけのアイディアを
決めていたなんて！
You came up with all that
in such a short time!
No…we haven't decided—
いや 決めてなど…。
(キラービー)あぁ～！
♪♪「俺様は 大事なことを
忘れてたぜ バカ野郎 この野郎」
Oh, I forgot something important.
Fool, ya fool.
For entertainment,
Brother might perchance…
♪♪「こっちは 余興で ブラザーが
雲隠れの舞 舞うとは思うまい」
perform the "Hidden Cloud Dance."
Yay.
♪♪「イエー！」
The Raikage…
雷影が…。
雲隠れの舞を舞う だと!?
The Hidden Cloud Dance, you say?!
No, no, no… no way, no way…
いや いや いや いや…
ない ない ない ない！
So now you get the drift…
♪♪「ざっと こんな感じ。
パーティー 盛り上がる暗示 イエー！」
How the party will get a lift, yay
T-This is bad! At this rate…
た… 大変です！ このままじゃ…。
Gaara will lose!
我愛羅が負けるじゃん！
No, giving a gift isn't
about winning or losing.
いや 祝うっていうのは
勝ち負けじゃない気が…。
Dance...
Huh?
踊りじゃん…。
(３人)えっ？
Show up the Raikage…
and dance too, Gaara!
雷影に対抗して
我愛羅も踊りで対抗すべきだろ！
That is the only way!
そうするしか
他に方法はありません！
(カカシ)そろそろ
水影も到着するとのことです。
The Mizukage should be arriving soon.
ならば
風影も呼んだほうがよいな。
Then we should call the Kazekage.
カカシ様。
様は やめてって。
Lord Kakashi…
Drop the "lord."
We received a request to
adjust the entertainment time
ナルト ヒナタ両人の結婚式で→
余興の時間を調整してほしい と
依頼が来ているのですが…。
allotted at Naruto and Hinata's
wedding reception.
Huh? What's that?
えっ!? 何？ それ。
How come I wasn't told about
a wedding reception?!
あいつらの披露宴のことなんて
俺 知らないよ。 誰の依頼？
At whose request?
It's from…Lord Raikage's bodyguard…
それが 雷影様の護衛の方で…。
なに!?
What?!
He mentioned
the "Hidden Cloud Dance" by the Raikage.
雷影様が 雲隠れの舞と
言ってましたからね。
Okay! Gaara will do
the "Hidden Sand Samba."
よし！ 我愛羅は
砂隠れのサンバでいくべきじゃん。
Oh! This is getting more
and more exciting.
おっ！
なんか ノリがよさそうですね。
Stop joking. I can't dance.
冗談を言うな。 踊りなどできるか。
Besides, it wouldn't make
Naruto happy.
そもそも
当のナルトたちは喜ばんだろう。
Actually, I think he might take
the initiative and join in.
むしろ 率先して
踊りに加わる気がするのですが。
W-What…?!
なんだと!?
Y-You're right.
Still…
確かに…。
いや いや いや！
The Kazekage shouldn't dance
in front of people!
かといって 風影が 人前で
踊るなんて おかしいでしょ！
But he said the Raikage
is going to dance!
しかし
雷影は踊るって言ってるじゃん！
♪♪「雷影の結婚祝い 雷影の舞」
The Raikage's gift of dance
is a must-see
♪♪「見なきゃ 絶対 時代に遅れる。
イエー！」
If you miss this opportunity,
behind the times you'll be, yay.
あのバカが…。
That fool!
失礼… これより 失態を
お見せするが ご容赦くだされ。
I beg your pardon if
I make a scene…
いや 雷影が
手を下す必要は なさそうじゃぞ。
No, I doubt there will be
a need for you to intervene.
♪♪「雷影の結婚祝い 雷影の舞」
DUMPLINGS
The Raikage's wedding gift
of dance is a must-see
♪♪「見なきゃ 絶対 時代に遅れる。
イエー！」
If you miss this opportunity,
behind the times you'll be, yay.
(メイ)結婚… 遅れる？
Wedding… Behind the times?
I'll kill you.
(メイ)殺すぞ！
(キラービー)ノー！
I now call this Five Kage
Conference to order.
それでは 五影会談を開始します。
However, before we begin…
ですが その前に…。
In regard to wedding gifts for
Naruto Uzumaki and Hinata Hyuga…
うずまきナルト 日向ヒナタの
結婚祝いは→
I ask that you use your good sense and
keep things in moderation.
常識的 かつ ほどほどにするよう
くれぐれもお願いいたします。
And so, let's move on
to our agenda.
(カカシ)では早速 今回の議題に
入りたいと思いますが…。
H-Hey…
(シカマル)よ よう。
S-Sorry about last time.
こないだは
なんか悪かったな。
No… I'm sorry as well.
いや こちらこそ。
メシ 行くか？
Want to get a bite to eat?
Might as well…
LEAF INN
(テマリ)仕方ないな。
RESERVED FOR
A SPECIAL EVENT TODAY
(テウチ)風影様 まだ木ノ葉の里に
いらしたんですね？
会談の時間がずれたのでな。
Lord Kazekage…
ひと晩
泊まっていくことになった。
So, you were still here in the village!
夜も うちのラーメンを
選んでくれるなんて→
The conference ran long…
ありがたいこってす。
So, I decided to stay the night.
ああ これほどの味は
食べたことがない。
I'm grateful that you've chosen
our ramen for dinner!
これ以上ないほめ言葉だ。
Well… I've never had anything
so delicious.
ところで聞きましたよ
ナルトたちの結婚祝いの件。
And I've never had such
a compliment.
火影様から
お達しがあったとか。
By the way, I heard about
the remarks Lord Hokage made
当然だ 祝い事とはいえ
はしゃぎすぎた。
about Naruto and Hinata's wedding gifts…
当人たちも 今頃
十分反省してることだろう。
It was to be expected.
Things were getting
out of hand.
I'm sure everyone's feeling
remorseful now.
この俺自身もな。
俺も 煽っちまったからな。
申し訳ねえ。
Even I…
気にしないでくれ。
And I went overboard too.
I apologize.
(テウチ)おっ！
イルカ先生 いらっしゃい。
Don't worry about it.
Oh! Iruka Sensei.
風影様 今の話
うかがいました。
Welcome!
俺からも
謝らせてください。
Lord Kazekage…
I just overheard you.
ナルトの先生まで。
I want to apologize too.
ここで お会いしたとき…。
But Naruto's teacher shouldn't…
((風影様が ナルトのために
盛大に祝ってくださるなんて→
When I met you last time…
(恐れ多いことですが
ナルトのやつも必ず喜ぶはずです))
I'm very grateful to
the Lord Kazekage
for making such
an extravagant gesture…
あんなことを言った俺にも
責任があります。
and I'm sure Naruto will
be overjoyed as well.
I'm at fault too,
for putting it like that.
本当に
申し訳ございませんでした。
いや 謝ることではない。
I'm very sorry.
ただ 単純に
嬉しかったんです。
There's nothing to be sorry about!
I was just…simply happy.
ナルトには立場を越えてまで
祝ってくれる→
I learned that Naruto
has wonderful friends
すばらしい友人が
いるんだということがわかって。
who will go above and beyond
to celebrate him.
友人か…。
Friends…huh.
本当に
ありがとうございます。
いや こちらこそ礼を言う。
え？
Thank you very much.
No, I want to thank you too.
何か曇っていたものが
晴れた気分だ。
Huh?
I was confused,
and you've cleared it up for me.
俺たちは
形式的なことばかり考えて→
I was thinking only
about appearances,
根本的なことを
忘れていたのかな。
and forgot the most basic thing.
どういうことです？
俺は風影としてではなく→
What do you mean?
I'm going to honor Naruto not
as the Kazekage,
ナルトの友人として祝わせてもらう。
but as his friend.
それでいいだろうか？
Would that be all right?
もちろんです。
Of course.
(テウチ)みそチャーシュー大盛り
ナルトトッピング おまちどお！
A large miso char siu ramen
with Naruto fishcake topping!
(我愛羅)ああ ありがとう。
(テウチ)イルカ先生は何にする？
Oh, thank you.
What'll you have, Iruka Sensei?
(イルカ)じゃあ俺も
みそチャーシュー大盛りに→
Make mine the same…
A large miso char siu ramen
with Naruto fishcake topping.
ナルトつけてください。
(テウチ)はいよ！
Coming right up!
Dad, I'm done cleaning up here.
お父さん？
こっちも掃除終わったわよ。
おう お疲れ。
まだ帰らないの？
Okay, thanks!
Not going home yet?
私 先帰るわよ。
戸締まり ちゃんとしてね。
I'm gonna go on ahead.
Make sure you lock up!
All right… Finished!
よし できた。
NARUTO CONGRATULATIONS
ALL YOU CAN EAT FOREVER
Have a safe trip back home.
それでは お気をつけて。
Gaara! Please come again!
我愛羅君
ぜひまた来てください！
It would be great if you come back
on your own next time,
今度は風影の執務じゃなく
お忍びで来られるといいですね。
and not on official
Kazekage business.
Yes, that won't be
too long from now.
そうだな それも
遠くはあるまい。
(２人)うん？
For Naruto and Hinata's wedding.
ナルトたちの結婚式→
I'm sorry, but I don't plan
on bringing
申し訳ないが
砂隠れの里からは→
a special gift from
the Hidden Sand.
特に祝いの品を
用意するつもりはない。
Huh? Why?
Let him finish!
えっ なんでだよ！
待ちなって。
I want to honor them personally,
as a friend.
俺は 個人的に
２人を祝おうと思う。
I think that will please Naruto more.
そのほうが ナルトは
喜ぶ気がしてな。
Gaara!
Gaara…
我愛羅君！
我愛羅…。
Yes, please do that.
ええ ぜひ
そうしてやってください。
I think it turned out for the best.
しかし これで
よかったんじゃないか？
Feels like everything's all settled!
You're in a good mood, Temari.
すべて
丸く収まった気がするぞ。
N-No, I'm not!
テマリは ずいぶん
機嫌がいいな。
Besides, seeing you so depressed
is more shocking, Kankuro!
そっ そんなことはない！
そんなことより
カンクロウが こんなに→
You can't blame him,
落ち込むことのほうが
驚きだろう！
since we're not going all out
with an extravagant gift.
盛大に祝えなくなったんだから
仕方あるまい。
No, that doesn't bother me.
I'm just disappointed we won't get
to see you dance, Gaara.
いや それは別に
いいじゃん。
No, there's still hope!
ただ我愛羅の踊りが
見られないのが残念じゃん。
He can dance as Naruto's friend!
いや まだ希望の芽はあるぞ。
友人として踊ってやればいい。
No chance.
はあ！
16 MORE DAYS UNTIL
THE WEDDING
フッ ないな。
To the one million
Shino fans out there,
I'm sorry to have
kept you waiting.
It's been said for over ten years